NYSUT Legislative Department Files. 6174/005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- New Local Presidents' Conference, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Agenda; list of attendees; related correspondence
- Committee of 100 (folder 1), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  2/24-25, 1992. Letters to attendees re housing arrangements; housing list of participants
- Committee of 100 (folder 2), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  2/24-25, 1992. Tentative agenda; facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100 Invitations, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  List of UFT participants; distribution list for invitations
- Legislative Reception, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  February 3, 1992. List of invitees; printed invitations; menu and facilitative correspondence
- Wantagh Retirees Meeting, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  12/14/1992. Letter of invitation to Ray Skuse to speak to retirees, to address several process issues
- NYS AFL-CIO Labor Recognition Dinner, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  12/3/1992. Program and invitation for 8th annual Labor Recognition Dinner; memos
- Yonkers Federal Workshop Arden House, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  11/7/1992. Memo to Ray Skuse re speaking at the Yonkers Federation of Teachers annual workshop re legislative issues
- Belle Zeller Scholarship Award Dinner, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  11/5/1992 NYC. Invitation to Friend of CUNY award dinner
- NYS AFL-CIO, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  8/30-9/3/1992. Program for 27th Constitutional Convention of NYS AFL-CIO; reservation form for NYSUT member
- Committee of 100 (folder 1), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  5/18-19, 1992. Agenda; memo from Ray Skuse inviting community college presidents to attend lobbying day; print request forms for materials including lists of members of Senate and Assembly higher education committees
- Committee of 100 (folder 2), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  5/18-19, 1992. Housing reply forms and other facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100 (folder 3), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  5/18-19, 1992. Housing lists and other facilitative correspondence
- Special Act Schools Lobby Day, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  March 4, 1992. Agenda for lobby day; letters of invitation to lobby day; list of Special Act Schools (for children with handicapping conditions) local presidents; list of state legislators representing districts with Special Act Schools; letter to deputy education commissioner re inequities in salary formulas for Special Act Schools; legislative alert to Coalition for Special Act School Districts re funding methodologies for Special Act Schools; clipping from New York Teacher, "Giving Troubled Youth a Future"
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  March 9-10, 1992. Agenda; schedule of appointments with legislators; list of NYSUT- affiliated community colleges as of 12/21/90; letters of invitation to community college locals; list of participating UUP members; list of attendees
- Federal Legislative Reception, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Printed invitations; list of legislators; briefing memo to reception attendees re legislative issues, including health care, vouchers, balanced budget amendment, striker replacement, with attached voting records of legislators
- Teacher Center Lobby Day, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  March 10, 1992. List of members of Senate and Assembly finance committees and associated teacher centers; text of proposed legislation; memo re suggested changes to draft legislation; memo from NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese re meeting of Teacher Center Policy board members and directors; related memos; testimony of NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson to the Senate Finance Committee and Assembly Ways and Means Committee on the 1992-93 Executive Budget
- New Local Presidents Conference, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Program; agenda; notes from the April 17 meeting of the New Local Presidents Conference Committee; time line and notes from May 28 committee meeting; conference call and registration form
- New Local Presidents Conference, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  July 18, 1990. Agenda; conference schedule; document, "1989-90 Invisible Victories: Bills Blocked by NYSUT That Would Have Destroyed Member Rights"; minutes of May 7 and June 11 planning committee meetings; topics for round table discussions at conference; program for 1989 conference
- Committee of 100, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  February 25-26, 1991. Facilitative correspondence; list of invited participants
- Committee of 100 Print Shop Requests, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  Print requests for materials for Lobby Day
- Federal Legislative Reception, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Printed invitations; response forms; list of invitees
- Higher Education Luncheon (folder 1), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  12/18/1991 Fort Orange Club. Letter from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson to legislators, discussing higher education funding, inviting them to lunch; list of invitees; menu
- Higher Education Luncheon (folder 2), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  12/18/1991. Letter from United University Professions (UUP) president to NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson re suggested issues for discussion at higher education meeting; document by Professional Staff Congress of City University of New York (PSCcuny), "Reaffirming CUNY's Mission"; bullet points for SUNY and CUNY; letters from Magidson to legislators
- Higher Education Lobbying (folder 1), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  2/19-20, 1991. Letters of invitation to Lobby Day to local presidents of community colleges; letters re chance in date to February 25-26
- Higher Education Lobbying (folder 2), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  2/19-20, 1991. Form letter of invitation
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  2/26-27, 1990. Agenda; list of participants; letter of invitation
- Legislative Reception, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  Printed invitations; letters of invitation to local presidents of community colleges; facilitative correspondence
- NYSUT Legislative Reception, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  2/5/1990 Corning Tower. Printed invitation; letters of invitation to community college local presidents; list of invitees; handwritten list of legislative staff; menu and other facilitative correspondence
- Federal Legislative Reception Representative Assembly, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Washington, DC. Printed invitation; program brochure for Representative Assembly; thank-you letters from NYSUT president Hobart to other NYSUT officers for moderating seminars; thank-you letters to members of Congress and others for participating; letters listing members of Congress and labor officials to attend seminars and panels
- Committee of 100-Vouchers, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  5/1991. Housing lists and expense forms for Committee of 100 participants
- Committee of 100-Invitations, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  May 13-14, 1991. Lists of retirees participating in Committee of 100 lobby day
- Committee of 100, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  May 13-14, 1991. Lists of attendees
- Committee of 100, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  May 13-14, 1991. NYSUT draft budget overview, "The Impact of Executive Proposals on State Aid to Public Education 1991-92"; draft, "1991 NYSUT Legislative Program for Pension Equity"; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson, discussing issues; related memos to retiree participants in Committee of 100 lobby day
- Committee of 100-Material for Kits, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  May 13-14, 1991. Print requests for ad/flyers, lists of legislators, and related materials for lobby day
- FNHP Lobbying, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  3/12-13, 1990. Agenda; list of participants; letter to participants; facilitative correspondence
- FNHP Lobbying, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  March 4-5, 1991. List of participants; letter to participants; facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  May 21-22, 1990 Hilton. Tentative agenda; issues briefing book, "NYSUT Program for Pension Equity," with cover letter to participants; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson; memo to Ray Skuse suggesting improvements; reporting form for visits with legislators; facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100 Retirees, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  Lists of participants; facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  March 5-6, 1990. Housing lists; facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  March 5-6, 1990. Agenda; housing lists; memo re media coverage
- AFT Convention, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Tentative program; facilitative correspondence
- Community College Lobbying, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  January 29-30, 1990. Letter of invitation to lobby day from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson to community college local presidents
- Federal Reception and Lobbying, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  5/8-9, 1990. Tentative agenda; talking points on issues; filled-in reporting forms noting reactions of individual legislators at lobbying meetings; list of attendees; facilitative correspondence with hotel staff
- UFT Steering Committee on Veterans' Pension Credit, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  June 12, 1990. Schedule of meetings with legislators
- Political Action Workshop-Utica, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Agenda; letter inviting NYSUT local leaders to regional workshop; letter inviting legislators to dinner; lists of attendees
- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  April 28-June 29, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail re legislative issues, including background briefing materials
- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  January 5-April 27, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  October 3-December 14, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  June 27-September 30, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  October 27-November 28, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  November 13-December 22, 1992. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  June 1-November 10, 1992. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  January 3-May 29, 1992. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  August 20-December 3, 1991. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  April 24-August 20, 1991. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  January 3-April 23, 1991. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  November 16-December 20, 1995. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  August 31-November 16, 1995. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  May 2-August 30, 1995. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  January 24-May 2, 1995. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  January. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  September-December. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  August-October. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  April-August. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  March-April. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  January-March. Chronological files of outgoing mail
- Costello, John (1 of 2), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Correspondence of John Costello, NYSUT assistant director of legislation, re Special Act schools, retiree contributions to VOTE/COPE, plans for 1997 legislative session; summary of report by American Economics Group, commissioned by NYSUT, "Our Tax System: Flawed and Unfair," re fiscal crisis generated by 1987 state tax cut; document, "Pension Supplementation," re bills in 1994 and 1995 legislative session
- Costello, John (2 of 2), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Draft document re BOCES issues; draft summary of campaign operations undertaken by Legislative Department; instructions for letter writing campaign in support of Mario Cuomo's re-election as governor, with sample letters; comparisons of state aid for 4201 Schools 1993-94 to 1994-95; description of 4201 issues; draft background information re health insurance for retired public and school employees; monthly VOTE/COPE coordinators report form
- Lewis, Alan, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Chronological correspondence of NYSUT legislative relations coordinator Alan Lewis re legislation, reports, referred resolutions
- Lewis, Alan, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Chronological correspondence re legislation
- Lewis, Alan, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Chronological correspondence re legislation, with text of amendments
- Lewis, Alan (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Compilation of legislation enacted 1973 through 1996 affecting members of NYS Teachers' Retirement System; memos re referred resolutions; documents re Federal Election Commission, union activities under federal campaign laws; memos re state regulations for lobbyists re salary and expense reporting; list of bills of interest passed in both state houses as of 11/12/96
- Lewis, Alan (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Proposed resolutions for 1996 Representative Assembly (RA); memo re implementation of resolutions referred at 1995 RA; legislative memoranda of support for various bills; memos re state lobbying reports; highlights of retirement incentive bill
- Kafka, Emanuel, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  1994 VOTE/COPE Instruction Manual; Outline of Presentation of Proposed National Health Security Act to Community Groups; Benefits Comparison under Health Security Act; memo to NYSUT Board of Directors re national health care; health care reform legislative update; list of NY congressional delegation; agenda for Clinton Health Security Plan Speakers Bureau Training Session; related materials
- Lewis, Alan, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Chronological correspondence
- Lewis, Alan, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Lewis, Alan, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Chronological correspondence re campaign contribution limits and related issues; memos to the governor re pending legislation
- Lewis, Alan, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Chronological correspondence and text of legislation re early retirement incentive, retirement benefits; legislation passed by both state houses awaiting action by governor as of 8/14/92; bills signed as of 8/14/92; bills vetoed as of 8/14/92
- Lewis, Alan, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Chronological correspondence re lobbying reports, retirement issues; text of proposed amendments re workers' compensation, maternity leave, other issues
- Lewis, Alan, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Chronological correspondence re NYSUT legislative program on a range of issues
- Martineau, Peter, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Chronological correspondence of NYSUT assistant director of legislation Peter Martineau re political and policy aspects of higher education issues
- Martineau, Peter, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Testimony of NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin at state legislative committee hearings re state budget, community colleges; correspondence re mental health issues; memos from Martineau to NYSUT officers re higher education and other legislative research
- Martineau, Peter, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Testimony of NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin at state legislative committee hearings re executive budget, future of State University of New York; letter from Martineau to counsel to Gov. Pataki re reforms supported by NYSUT, August 17; letter to locals praising turnout for Clinton/Gore rally; memo to UUP president re variable tuition report, December 19
- Martineau, Peter (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Text of legislation re workers' compensation, medical monitoring; memos from Martineau to NYSUT officers re media coverage of SUNY, political critique of AFT brochure on higher education, other issues; list of status of legislation at end of session, 7/20
- Martineau, Peter (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Chronological correspondence re higher education and budget issues
- Skuse, Ray, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Document, "History of labor laws in NYS for public employees"; draft policy re local political activities, with question and answer sheet; status report on key NYSUT initiatives; text of bill re teacher resource centers, 1992; papers analyzing proposed legislation re retirement, state aid; chronological correspondence
- Skuse, Ray, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Chronological correspondence including letters to local presidents re political action workshop
- Skuse, Ray, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Chronological correspondence re NYC school construction and higher education capital bond issues; progress report on Dukakis presidential campaign phone calling by region, October 12; draft press release announcing endorsement of state Sen. James Donovan (R)
- Skuse, Ray, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Final report, 1987 Legislative Session: NYSUT Program and Support Bills Signed into Law; Random Notes re Election of Delegates to the Democratic Convention and Congressional District Coordinators; memorandum of opposition to proposed legislation allowing school districts to require fingerprinting of employees and prospective employees; chronological correspondence
- Skuse, Ray, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Chronological correspondence including draft responses to letters to the editor criticizing NYSUT endorsement process, October 10, 1986; memos re election telephone calling operation; regional high schools of excellence, 1985; analysis of civil service and pension proposals; memo re proposed New York State Voter Registration Network, meeting with District Council 37 political director Norman Adler, Bella Abzug, Democratic party officials, and legislators, May 23, 1983, with attached documents re need to target black population in NY as largest unregistered segment in U.S.
- Support Statements-Bills Not Carried Over from 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Summaries of proposed legislation and statements of support by NYSUT
- Legislation (Ventura), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Proposals for retirement/pension equity, 1990-1992; 1993 Final Report on NYSUT's major legislative program and support bills; Legislative Update: Highlights of Previous NYSUT Legislative Victories, April 1993; related documents apparently stored on Ventura computer system
- Ballard, Pat, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  List of NYSUT affiliated community colleges; memo from Ballard to Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals (FNHP) leaders re NYS budget highlights, May 8, 1992; testimony of presidents of CUNY Professional Staff Congress and United University Professions (UUP) at state legislative committee hearings; documents re community college statistics, items of interest to UUP, sexual harassment criteria
- Ballard, Pat, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Draft Comprehensive Report, Legislation of Interest to Higher Education and Health Care Professionals; memo from Ballard to NYSUT president Tom Hobart re SUNY community colleges and state aid data, March 15; memo re Adolescent Tobacco Act, October 5; memo from Ballard to FNHP members, summary of 1990 legislative session, September 17; highlights of SUNY and CUNY state operations budgets and related fact sheets; testimony of officers of higher education labor unions at state legislative committee hearings
- Ballard, Pat, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  Executive Budget Highlights of Health Care Proposals; Major Legislation of Interest: Higher Education and Health Care Professionals, 1989 and 1988; memo suggesting facts re SUNY community colleges for inclusion in VOTE/COPE pamphlet; tentative schedule and workshop descriptions for "Effective Unions in Community Colleges," November 3-5, 1989; memo re Legislative Department's activities for UUP, 1989-90; materials re letter-writing campaign to elected representatives; materials re lobbying day
- Ballard, Pat (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Letters to community college local presidents re meeting to discuss lobbying for SUNY and CUNY budget requests; list of bills of interest to higher education, signed by governor, October 27; Position Statement on the Use of Laboratory Animals in Biomedical Research, prepared by UUP; memos re budget issues
- Ballard, Pat (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Reports on CUNY and SUNY state aid; letters to state legislators from NYSUT and UUP officers; letters to community college presidents re budget issues; memo re lobbying day by Committee of 100
- Ballard, Pat, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  List of legislators invited to UUP legislative breakfast (lobbying), January 26; memo from Ballard to Legislative Director Ray Skuse, "Highlights of SUNY's Undergraduate Initiative," December 7; draft documents, "Governor's Initiative to Promote Teaching Excellence at the State University of New York and the City University of New York"; memo from Ballard to UUP's Legislative Committee summarizing items of interest; memo from Ballard reporting on AFT Community College Conference, October 23-25; legislative memorandum of support for SUNY state aid proposal; final reports of 1987 legislative session; other materials related to CUNY and SUNY budget issues
- Ballard, Pat, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  Memo from Ballard to NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson summarizing final report of AFT task force on future of health care, September 21; memo and notice of Assembly Committee hearing on community colleges; notes for upcoming meeting with legislators on higher education; summaries of executive budget re higher education; document, legislation of interest to higher education and health care professionals; detailed analysis of health care state aid, 1991-92, for internal use by NYSUT Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals; agenda for FNHP lobbying day, March 4-5; list of Senate and Assembly Health Committee members
- Ballard, Pat, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Chronological correspondence re repeal of mandatory retirement age for tenured faculty, humane animal experimentation task force recommendations, SUNY Maritime College, certification of health teachers, Monroe Community College capital construction request; final reports on governor's action on major legislation of interest to SUNY-CUNY community colleges, UUP, PSC; highlights of 1986 tax reform proposal of interest to higher education faculty
- Ballard, Pat, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  NYSUT Legislative Program and Support Bills of Interest to Community Colleges, 1983 and 1984; final reports for 1985 session; bills of interest to UUP that were signed into law, 1983 session; text of mailgram to U.S. senators Moynihan and D'Amato opposing tuition tax credit for private school enrollment, November 9, 1983; memo from Ballard (Koenig) re first impressions of executive budget proposals, January 1984; detailed analyses of state budget proposals impacting SUNY and CUNY; update of 1984 legislative session
- Ballard, Pat, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Testimony of president of United College Employees of the Fashion Institute of Technology to the NYS Assembly Committee on Higher Education and Subcommittee on Community Colleges, October 23, 1991; testimony of SUNY chancellor D. Bruce Johnstone before the committees; State of New York multi-year financial update, fiscal year 1991-92; material re VOTE/COPE; update of 1991-92 session; agenda for FNHP legislative meeting, December 6
- Connolly, Kristan, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  List of school districts by Senate district and Assembly district; budget cut impact survey (layoffs) by local; document re BOCES reform legislation
- Costello, John, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 5)